Loops in programming are a way of repeating actions.
プログラミングするうえで、ループは何かのアクションを反復する手段です。
Let's look at three different kinds of loop.
いろいろな種類のループをみていきましょう。
A For Loop, a While Loop and a Do While Loop.
For ループ、While ループ、および Do While ループです。
All of the loop examples are attached to
今回のサンプルのすべてのループは
a gameobject and we will check the
ゲームオブジェクトにアタッチされていて、
response in the console.
コンソールで結果を確認していきます。
First off let's take a look at a While Loop.
最初に While ループをみてきましょう。
The While Loop is used to simply perform
While ループはある条件が満たされた
an action whilst a condition is met.
アクションを実行するのに使用されます。
In this example we have a variable
このサンプルでは cupsInTheSink とい名前の
called cupsInTheSink.
変数があります。
We have 4 cups in the sink.
シンク に 4 つのカップがあるとします。
While the number of cups in the sink
シンクにある カップの数が
is more than 0 we need to wash them up.
0 である場合、それらを洗う必要があるとします。
So we're simply looking for ''I've wash a cup!''
''I've washed a cup!'' (カップを洗った)とログを残して、
and subtracting 1 from the value
sink 変数 でのカップの値から
of our cups in the sink variable.
1 を引きます。
So this loop will continue 4 times
このループが 4 回反復されるのは
as we have 4 cups. Let's see this in action.
コップが 4 つあるためです。
And you can see we've washed up 4 cups.
そして 4 つのカップを洗ったことを確認できます。
Next let's take a look at
次に Do While ループを
the Do While Loop.
みてきましょう。
The Do While Loop is similar to the While loop
Do While ループは While Loop に似てますが
but sometimes it's important to perform an
アクションを必ず 1 回は実行して
action at least once, and then perform
それから、さらに条件が満たされたときに
further iterations of a loop whilst
ループを反復することが
the condition is met. In this example
重要な場合があります。
we are trying to guess an age
ここでは年齢を 25 から 30 才の間で
between 25 and 30.
推測しようとします。
We've put in the correct age of 27.
正しい年齢は 27 と入力しました。
And we have an integer for guessing age.
さらに 年齢を推測する integer があります。
The Do While Loop in this instance
この場合の Do While ループは
runs the guess function
Guess 関数を実行して
until the guessAge meets the correct age.
guestAge が正しい年齢になったときに完了します。
So we're doing guess whilst the guessAge
いいかえると guessAge が正しい年齢に等しくない間は
is not equal to the correct age.
ループを反復します。
When this condition is no longer met
この条件が満たされなくなったとき
we move on to the next line of the script
スクリプトの次の行に進んで
which logs ''Correct! I'm'' and the correct age.
ログとして ''Correct! I'm'' （正解！私の年齢は）と、正しい年齢を残します。
So the guess is simply saying assign guessAge
このため Guess では guessAge を
a random range between 25 and 30
25 から 30 までランダムな範囲で割り当てて
and then we're adding or subtracting
それから足すか引くかして
to try and guess that age, and then we're
正しい年齢を推測して、
logging a guess of a particular
特定の年齢の推測を
age in to the console.
コンソール出力しています。
Let's see what this does.
それではこの結果をみてみましょう。
So you can see that we've guessed 28
これで 28 を推測して、
then we've guessed 27. 27 was correct
次に 27 を推測したことが分かります。 27 は正しい年齢なので
so the Do While Loop finishes
Do While ループは終了して、
and we print ''Correct! I'm 27!''.
ログに ''Correct! I'm 27!'' と残します。
Let's see that again.
もう 1 回みてみましょう。
And you can see we're getting a deviation
今回はちょっと違う結果であることが分かります。
because random will guess a number of
これは Random が推測で違う数字を
different times and you can see it's
推測したためで、今回は
tried 25, then 26 and finally 27
25, 26, そして最後に 27 の順で試したことが分かります。
which has been verified to be correct.
27 は正解でした。
Next the For Loop. This is probably the most
次に For ループです。これはおそらく
common and flexible loop.
もっとも一般的かつ柔軟なループです。
The For Loop works by introducing a
For ループは
controllable number of iterations to a loop.
制御可能なループを反復することができます。
Functionally, it begins by checking
機能的には、最初に
conditions in the loop, seen here as
ループの条件をチェックします。
i < numEnemies.
ここでは条件は i < numEnemies です。
And if the condition is met it
そして条件が満たされたとき
carries out the instructions in the loops body,
ループの中における指示を実行します。
meaning what is between the curly braces.
ループの中とは、 {} にある内容です。
After each loop, known as an iteration,
各々のループ、すなわち反復の後、
it can optionally increment a value,
オプションとして、値を増加させることが出来ます。
seen here in the third argument where
ここでは 3 つめの引数で
i is being incremented by 1 each time.
i が 毎回 1 だけ増加させます。
This process then starts over.
このプロセスはもう 1 回実行されます。
Let's look at this from a coding standpoint.
これをコーディングの観点からみていきます。
The syntax for this has three arguments.
この構文には 3 つの引数があります。
First off we introduce a variable,
最初に変数を使用します。
this is known as the iterater.
これは反復子（iterator）として知られます。
This is used to count through the iterations
これはループの反復をカウントするのに使用され、
of the loop, meaning the loops themselves.
すなわち、何回目のループまで実行したか、です。
The second argument is the condition
二つめの引数はループを継続するため
that must be true in order for the loop
に true となる必要のある
to continue.
条件です。
Finally the third argument defines
最後に 3 つめの引数は
what happens to the iterater
毎回の iterator が各々のループでどうなるか、です。
in each loop. Usually this means adding to
通常は
the iterater in order to step
ループをステップ実行していくにあたり
through the loop. It's common in
iterator を増加させます。
programming to start counting at 0.
プログラミングにおいてカウントを 0 から始めることは一般的です。
So for the first loop, i will be 0
最初のループでは i が 0 であり、
and then the operation i++ adding 1 to i
i++ という演算によって i に 1 が追加されます。
will be performed. Then on the second loop
さらに 2 つめの i のループは 1 となり、
i will be 1, and so on.
そのように反復していきます。
Until i is no longer less than, in this example,
これは i が
the numEnemies variable.
numEnemies 変数よりも小さくなるまでループは続きます。
So we have an integer called numEnemies,
このため numEnemies という変数があり、
which is set to 3, so once this loop
3 がセットされていて、このループが
has happened 3 times i will be equal to
3 回実行されると
the value of numEnemies and therefore the loop
num Enemies の値と同じになり、
will not be run again as the validation
ループは再び実行されなくなり、
condition will be false.
その理由は条件式が false となるためです。
So we will not see the message creating
このため enemy の数字が 3 であると
enemy number 3 in the console
コンソールでメッセージをみることはなく、
because when i is equal to 3
その理由は i が 3 と等しいとき、
it will no longer be less than numEnemies
numEnemies より小さいという条件は満たされないためであり、
and so it will not run the
loopBodies コマンドを
loopBodies commands.
実行しなくなります。
In this example we're logging the value of
このサンプルでは
i to the console, along side the text
i の値とその横に
''Creating enemy number''.
''Creating enemy number'' をコンソール出力します。
To demonstrate it's addition as well as
これによって i が増加していることと、
potential practical application of a loop.
ループの実際の場面での使用方法が確認できます。
Put simply, any operation that you need
簡単にいうと、
carried out a defined number of times
何回か行なう処理は
should be placed within a For Loop.
For ループの中で行なうべきです。
Let's see this in action.
実行しているところをみていきましょう。
And you can see it logs 3 times.
これで 3 回ログを残していることが分かります。
First, showing the value of i as 0
最初に i の値を 0 として表示して
then 1 and then 2.
次に 1, それから 2 とします。
So there's a lot of flexibility in what you
異なるループにより出来ることには
can do with different loops and
柔軟性と幅があり、
you should always consider using them when
異なるアクションを、
repeating different actions based on
特定の条件で反復する時に
certain conditions.
使用することを考えるべきです。 (翻訳:gamesonytablet)